# Jordi Burgos López

# Senior Software Engineer

I am a passionate developer. Regularly, I enjoy attending conferences and meetups to keep me up to date. Besides, I like to develop personal projects to improve my knowledge. I like to work with people, I am nice and easy to work with. In addition I have experience training and mentoring team members.

## Experience

2019-Present Lead Software Development Engineer, Mastercard, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 18.600 employees; Financial Services, Technology.

- Next Edge: Research and Development of the next generation of Mastercard payment network.
  - Engage with stakeholders (Enterprise Architecture, Shared Services and Security) to drive and understand implications for the new network.
  - Investigate and implement several POC with Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis and Spring Boot
- Event Framework: Research and Development to enable building applications using event driven
  - As we work to enable building applications that leverage an event driven architecture and also streamline the developer journey for such applications, we endeavor to provide a supporting application framework such that business functionality can be delivered with the simplest, smallest coding effort. The business functionality is currently envisioned to be delivered as a simple jar. To realize this simple development model, the application frameworks, messaging platforms, security services and tools required to deliver, integrate and operate applications will be integrated into an application framework that provides all of the boilerplate code and "plumbing" necessary to achieve required security and operational requirements. We refer to this as the Event Framework.
  - To achieve this goal we will use standards based frameworks, tools and patterns to ensure the sustainability of the platform.
- Service design bootstraping: AAAA
  - Service design bootstraping (Vulcan + vulcan-cli/Polaris) Lead, strategy + design
  - Vulcan is a tool to allow developers to quickly set up a new project by choosing the use-cases their application will implement.
  - The goal of the Paved Path is to enable developers across all teams in Mastercard focus on writing the required business functionality that our customers require, in a consistent way, in accordance with the Engineering Principles. More elaboration about this can be found on this article from Steve Bagby, CTO Enterprise Architecture.

#### 2016–2019 **Senior Software Engineer**, *SAP*, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 85.000 employees; Business Operations and Customer Relations.

- o SAP Analytics Cloud: Collect and produce statistics for dataset fields and metadata search. Java, Spring, JMS, REST, SAP HANA SQL.
  - Design and implement service architecture using Spring and JMS.
  - Design database structure and analysis SQL queries.
  - Implement service to support several cloud providers.
- o Predictive Analytics: Software to create Machine Learning and Big Data processing pipelines graphically. Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Webpack, SAP HANA database, SAP UI5.
  - Design and implement user interface architecture with Webpack and SAP UI5.
  - Implement application functionality in Typescript.
  - Train and supervise junior developers in the team.
  - Investigate and resolve bugs from server side code base.
  - Identify platform improvements and document them.

#### 2014–2016 **Senior Software Engineer**, *IBM*, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 400.000 employees; IT consulting.

- HR suite project: Software suite for HR related applications. Java, REST, JPA, JAX-RS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, IBM WebSphere, Linux.
  - Design and implement architecture of back-end REST services with JAX-RS and JPA on WebSphere servers.
  - Design and implement AngularJS user interface with connection to the REST back-end.
  - Investigate and select the best technologies suitable for the project.
  - Collaborate with User Experience (UX) team on the design of interface.
  - Work using Agile and Test Driven methodology.

#### 2006–2014 Java Software Engineer, GFT IT Consulting, S.L.U., Valencia, Spain.

Multinational Company; 4.800 employees; IT and Services industry.

- o Global Funds Derivatives Tracker: Capture fund derivatives business at Deutsche Bank. It is a repository of core funds, market data, derivatives, executed trades and documentation. Java, Spring, Hibernate, Oracle PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, ExtJS, Linux.
  - Agile methodology using Scrum to build technical solutions for banking applications.
  - Create reusable components and code to increase developers performance.
  - Optimize the application at all levels: presentation, communications and database.
  - Provide technical support to team members.
- o Feed Consolidation Layer: ETL project to fetch data from several sources in proprietary formats into a unified data representation. Java, Oracle PL/SQL, OpenAdaptor, Maven, Teamcity, Linux.
  - Improve feed processing performance to increase message volume with the same infrastructure.
  - Design and perform application deployments on Linux servers.
  - Analyse and improve the Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC) for Source Control, Build Tools, Binary Control, Release Automation, Automated Testing and Continuous Integration.
- o Legal Vehicle Database: Track legal entity population for tax reporting purposes at Deutsche Bank. Java, GWT, Hibernate, Oracle.
  - Rewrite the user interface of an inherited project using Google Web Toolkit (GWT).
  - Collaborate with software developers to deliver with adjusted deadline.
- o Multichannel Platform: Custom middleware that allows heterogeneous access to the bank mainframe resources of Bradesco Bank. Java, Eclipse Plug-in Development Environment.
  - Develop an Eclipse plugin which facilitate the location and communication of the processes that the platform of distribution of the channels exports or publishes.

#### 2001–2005 **Java Developer**, *Infoquip S.L.*, Valencia, Spain.

Local company; 5 employees; Computer material store and custom software development.

- o Java Program Generator: Java application generator to cut delivery times. Java, Swing, JDBC, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Linux.
  - Design and develop the engine for code generation.
  - Develop a report generator, with viewer and printer.
  - Design database to store application information and configuration.
- Sales point program for furniture company. Java, Swing, JDBC, MySQL.
  - Sales program for interconnected stores.
  - Take client requirements.
  - Develop application using generator and adapt according to the client requirements.

#### 1999–2000 **Technical School internship**, *Infoquip S.L.*, Valencia, Spain.

Local company; 5 employees; Computer material store and custom software development. Internship. 250 Hours.

• Learn Java programming language. Build and configure PCs and networks.

## Professional certification

- Jun-2018 Deep Learning and Neural Networks Specialization on Coursera
- Sep-2016 Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera

Jan-2009 Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform SE 6

Apr-2013 MongoDB for Java Developers Jul-2012 Object Oriented Analysis and Design with UML

Mar-2011 Oracle PL/SQL Developer Certified Associate

OCA PL/SQL

M101J

SCJP 6.0

Education

2004–2007 Master of Computer Science, Universidad Politécnica, Valencia, Spain.

2005 **ERASMUS grant**, *University College of Engineering*, Odense, Denmark.

2000–2004 Bachelor of Computer Science, Universidad Politécnica, Valencia, Spain.

1997–2000 Technical School Management Information Systems, I.E.S. El Cabañal, Valencia, Spain.

1996–1997 Technical School Administrative Assistant, I.F.P. La Marxadella, Torrente, Spain.

1995 Primary School Graduated, C.P. Ausiàs March, Picaña, Spain.

# Languages

English First Certificate English (FCE)

Level B2 CEFR, Jul-2012

Spanish Native Catalan Native

### Skills

Languages Java (J2SE, J2EE), JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Shell, scripting languages

Web REST, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, AngularJS, SAP UI5

Frameworks Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate

Operating Linux, Windows, Docker

Systems

Databases Oracle SQL and PL/SQL, MySQL, SAP HANA

Version Control Git, Subversion (SVN), CVS

Testing Unit Testing, Integration Testing, JUnit, Mockito, Selenium, Karma, Mocha

Methodology Agile software development, Scrum, Test Driven Development

Servers Apache Tomcat, WebSphere, Jetty

Build Tools Maven, Gradle, Ant, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp

Continuous Jenkins, Teamcity

Integration